# **USMAN TAHIR**



itsusmantahir1999@gmail.com



03095016490



linkedin.com/in/usman-tahir-a80b5121a



https://usmantahir.netlify.app/

## **Summary**

Experienced Software Quality Assurance with over 1 years of experience a demonstrated history of working in the Software Industry in different technologies (like web2.0,web3.0,wordpress,android,ios and game) in different types of software(like e-commerce website and application, Wallpaper and Themes apps, Rental Guarantee website) as Automation and Manual Testing.

# **Experience**



### **Software Quality Assurance Engineer**

Cherry Byte Technologies

Jun 2022 - Present (8 months)

Manual Testing of Multiple websites, web applications, game and mobile applications

Database Testing(MANUAL) of Multiple websites, web applications and mobile applications through MYSQL Workbench

API Testing of Multiple websites, web applications and mobile applications through POSTMAN Automation Testing of Multiple websites, web applications through JEST and CYPRESS

# Sales Sales

## **Software Quality Assurance Engineer Intern**

Black Box Labz

Mar 2022 - May 2022 (3 months)

Manual Testing of Multiple websites, mobile applications and game

Create detailed, comprehensive and well structured test cases

Estimate, prioritize, plan and coordinate testing activities.

Review and analyze user stories to determine reason-ability, test-ability, resource requirements

Bug reporting and verification of bugs reported

Documenting all the issues and their fixes

### **Education**



#### Lahore Garrison University

Bachelor's of Software Engineering(BSSE), Computer Software Engineering Sep 2017 - Sep 2021

#### Skills

Manual Testing • Jira • Agile Methodologies • Scrum • SQL • Database Testing • API Testing • Postman API • JavaScript • Cypress.io